カイジたち４５組は
正規の給料を取り返すため
Kaiji and the 45s, to win back their proper salaries, band together in shared sacrifice!
忍耐の３ヵ月を共にしのぐと宣言
Losers among losers, men trapped at the bottom of the abyss,
負け組の中の負け組
どん底の男たちは
打倒大槻のために今 立ち上がる！
they now stand forth to overthrow Ohtsuki!
Abuse and Endurance
勝つために！
生まれ変わるために！
To win!
To be reborn!
捨てた！惰性の安息を！
They abandon their habitual respites!
耐える！飲み食いしている
仲間を尻目に 耐える！
They endure!
Endure the suspicious glares from their comrades who partake!
Four for each of us, one peanut a piece.
１人４個ずつだ
ただしピーナッツは１つずつ
いいな？
Okay?
基本的に金はカイジが
In general, Kaiji handles the money,
タバコは前田が
Maeda the cigarettes,
and Miyoshi the candies.
甘い物は三好が管理
They survive sharing their meager rations.
少ないブツを
互いに分け合って暮らす
Of course, gambling and drinking are forbidden!
当然 バクチ 酒は御法度！
連中 結束してクリアする気ですよ
給料前借り生活を
Looks like they think they can pay back their advances.
フフフ… 続かない続かない
They'll never hold.
仮に続いたって
こいつで殺せば それまで
Even if they do, I'll finish them off with these dice.
プハー　フフフ…
カイジ 看護当番の日のこと
Kaiji's turn to attend to the ill arrives.
You're Kaiji, right?
あんた カイジさんだろ？
え？
(咳)
エスポワール 生き残り組の
Kaiji Ito, the one who survived the Espoir?
伊藤カイジ
ああ…
Yeah.
そう伝え聞いて
話がしたいと思っていた
Then I have something I need to tell you.
俺は石田広光
I'm Hiromitsu Ishida.
あんたに船で世話になった
石田光司の息子だ
The son of Koji Ishida, who you saved on that ship.
あっ そういえば面影ある！
あるある！
Oh, now I remember!
Yeah, yeah!
へー こんな大きな息子さんが
いたんだ
I never thought his son would be this big already!
そっくりだなー 石田さんに
You look just like your dad.
今 笑っただろ　腹ん中で
You're laughing at me, aren't you?
え？
親子揃って落ちぶれてやがるって
Laughing at how I've fucked up just as bad as my father did.
と… とんでもない！何を急に
No way! Why are you—
あれほど…
I didn't want to be that much like him!
あれほど親父のようには
なりたくなかったのに
クソッ 奴がちゃんとしていれば
Dammit!
If he had straightened out, I never would have ended up here!
こんなとこに落ちることは
なかったんだ
こんなとこに… こんなとこに
こんなとこに！
I never ever would have ended up in a place like this!
か… 肩代わりしたのか？
親父さんの借金
So you inherited your father's debt?
バカな！何で俺がそんなこと
しなきゃいけねえんだ！
No way! Why would I get stuck with that!?
冗談じゃない　俺の借金は300！
Gimme a fucking break!
My debt is three million!
え？
借金は
I went into debt gambling... And then this and that happened...
俺のバクチとか あと色々…
だったらここに落ちたのは お前の
責任じゃねえの？どう考えても
So really, it's your own fault you're down here, right?
No! You don't understand!
違う 分かってない
え？
My debt is three million! Just three million!
俺の借金は300！
たかだか300万なんだ！
それぐらいの はした金
払うだろ普通 親なら！
Normally I could just get that from my parents!
なのに奴ときたら 泣きそうな顔を
するだけで何もできない
But when I asked him, all he did was sit there looking like he was about to cry!
しばらくしたら何とかするって
おん出て それっきりだ
He said to wait and he'd try to do something, and that was it!
あ… それっていつ？
When was—
え？船から戻って
しばらくしてからだから
I've been waiting since right after he came back from the ship, so...
去年の７月頃だよ
Around last July.
Then... He must have...
そうか やっぱり！
あの橋で死んだんだ
He must have died on that girder...
あの時 石田さんは
懸命に精算しようとしていた
He was trying his hardest to clear his debts then!
何とかしたかった
He wanted to help out...
Not just with his own debts, but with his son's!
自分の借金 そして息子の借金を
たった300万ぽっち
払えよ それくらい
It's only three mil! Just fuckin' pay it!
Even going to college would have been cheaper compared to this!
大学に行ったことを考えりゃ
安いもんだろ
Dammit! Dammit dammit dammit dammit!
クソ！クソ クソ クソ
ずっと奴みたいには
なるまいと思ってた
I told myself I wouldn't end up like him!
Ever since I was a little kid...
ガキの頃から ずっと
なのに気づいたら
風体からダメさ加減まで
But you're laughing at me because I look just like him and I'm as much of a failure as he was!
そっくりだってんだから
笑わせやがる
フフフ… まるで呪いだぜ
This is a curse... A terrible curse...
タチの悪い呪い
何しやがる！
バカ野郎！
What the hell are you doing!?
Retard!
You're just like your dad? Bullshit!
お前と親父さんがそっくりだと？
笑わせるな！
まるで違うじゃないか
You're totally different!
You're scum! You blame everyone else for your problems!
お前は何でもかんでも
他人のせいにする クズ
親父さんは そんな人間じゃない
Your father wasn't that kind of man!
He accepted his weakness, his failures, and kept fighting!
自分の弱さ ダメさ加減を
全部 受け入れて戦ってたんだ
ふざけるな！別物
So don't give me that shit!
You're different!
まるで別物だ　話にならねえ
Completely different!
Not even worth mentioning in the same breath!
クソッ
Shit!
いやー わしも色々
男を見てきたけど
I've known a lot of men, but Kaiji is the best among them.
ピカイチは カイジ君だな
うん カイジ君　彼は大物だ
He's the real thing.
チッ 何が大物だ
What the hell do you mean, real thing?
He looks like just an ordinary guy, but I dunno.
パッと見は平凡な男だけど
何というか
カイジ君は逆境に
強いっていうかさ 諦めないのよ
When the chips are down, he's the one you want on your side.
He never gives up.
No matter what depths of despair he finds himself in...
たとえそれが
どんな絶望的な状況でも
１週間後 石田の息子 広光は
現場に復帰していた
One week later.
Ishida's son Hiromitsu returns to work.
He had overworked himself momentarily in order to secure a break!
彼は疲労がたまると仮病を使い
病棟で休んでいたのだ
それが彼のここでの
しのぎ方だった
This is how he survives here!
けど 奴はＥ班の借金組で
I've heard he's one of the debtors of E Team,
その借金を無理やり返そうと
仲間と無給で頑張ってるらしいが
and he's fasting with his friends to pay those loans off...
What an idiot!
何それ？大バカじゃん
できるわけがない
That'll never work!
そんなマネしたら 金を貸している
Ｅ班の班長の気分を害するだけだ
All that's going to do is piss off the E Team foreman who lent them the money!
Idiot!
バカが！
親父は何も分かってない
Worshiping that idiot like a hero? My dad didn't know anything!
あんなバカを
英雄視してるんだからな
コラ！何だお前たちは？
それでシャワー浴びたのか？
Hey!
What's wrong with you all? You call that showering!?
汗臭いぞ
え？
You smell like mud!
ダメだ それじゃ　やり直せ
No good! Do it again!
Kaiji and the others reluctantly return to the showers!
カイジたちは
渋々 シャワー室へ行き
And then, twenty minutes later!
そして20分後
あの 俺たちの食事は？
Um, where's our food?
そんなもの あるか
え？
You expect food?
遅いんだよ お前ら
You're late, and the rules here are that you don't get food if you're late to dinner!
ここの規則で 所定の時間内に
着席できなかった者には
食事させないことになってるんだ
クッ…
Idiots! If they give the higher-ups trouble, of course they're going to get this kind of shit!
バカが　上に逆らえば
この手の嫌がらせは当然さ
どうした どうした？
What's going on?
いや 奴らが食事の時間に
遅れてきまして
They came late for dinner.
うん それはいかんともしがたいな
規則だからな
Well, well. That's against the rules.
しかしどうかな
正規の食事はダメでも
But even if they miss their meal, why can't they stay for ours?
わしらが特注した料理なら
構わないんじゃないか？
え？
これは帝愛グループの縛りの外
This doesn't come from the Teiai Group. It's entirely our own thing.
もう わしらのものなんだから
Then it should be fine.
ああ それでしたら…
だろ？
Right?
How about it, Kaiji?
どうだね カイジ君
ここはひとつ 我々と一緒に
Care to share a meal with us?
Kaiji...
カイジさん
Give them one taste of luxury,
ぜいたくを一度 味わわせて
倹約節制の糸を切ろうって魂胆
陥落へのゆさぶり
and they'll abandon their frugality and fall back into their old ways.
見え見えだけど うまいんだよな
あの班長
It's pretty obvious, but he's got great delivery.
その切り札を出すﾀｲﾐﾝｸﾞというか
持っていき方がさ
Playing a card like that is all in the timing.
いやいやいや すまなかったな
Really, I'm sorry about the shower thing, but let's let bygones be bygones.
シャワーの一件は謝るよ
まっ 勘弁してくれ
さっ 座って座って
Now go ahead! Sit right down!
たまには肉も食わんとな
Man can't live on bread alone, you know!
それに こいつも
ずいぶん やってないだろ
And how long has it been since you've had a drink?
C'mon, chug it right down! There's plenty more where it came from!
さっ グーッとやってくれ
グーッと
言っとくが 金なんかねえぜ
You do know I can't afford this, right?
What are you talking about? I couldn't take money for this.
何を言ってるんだ
金なんか取るもんか
This is entirely out of my good will!
これは100パーセント
善意のビールだ
最近 カイジ君
ちょっとおかしかったろ？
You've been acting funny lately.
わしゃ ただそんなカイジ君と
仲直りしたいだけ
I just want to make up with you!
それだけなんだ
好きにしていいってことだな？
So you're saying I can do whatever I want with it?
え？
これ
This beer?
あ… ああ もちろんだ
Of course! Go right ahead!
さあ いってくれ 一気に
あぎゃ！
ああ 班長！
The foreman!
ど… どうぞ
フフフ…
Here.
ってことだ　遠慮なく
好きにさせてもらったぜ
Thanks, I needed that.
待て コラ！
ただで済むと思ってんのか 貴様！
Hold it!
Don't think you'll get away with this!
許してやれよ 石和
Forgive him, Isawa.
I wasn't in any danger.
わしの身に
危険が迫ったわけではない
それに万事穏便に済ませることが
班長たる者の務めだ
And it's a foreman's duty to make sure that things are settled quietly.
But...
しかし…
考えてもみろ
Plus, think about it. The company has this cafeteria under surveillance camera.
ここは常に組織側から
カメラで監視されてる食堂
Somewhere with no cameras like the toilets or blind spots on the work site would be better.
カメラの目が届かぬトイレや
現場の死角のような所なら
いざ知らず
こんな所で暴力沙汰など
できるはずもない
We can't be violent here.
カイジ君は ここんとこ
続けてた節制のストレスで
The stress of fasting like this must have made poor Kaiji have a breakdown.
精神のバランスが崩れておるんだ
He would never be so insolent otherwise.
でなければ
あんな無礼をする道理がない
彼は今 自分で自分が何を
してるのかよく分かってないんだ
He simply doesn't understand what he's doing.
Or how it makes the other person involved feel.
その行為が相手に
どういう感情を生むかもな
明らかに精神失調状態
He's obviously having a mental breakdown.
だから 許してやろうじゃないか
So we should let it slip, just this once.
寛容な精神で
It's only generous, right?
なあ？フフフ…
The foreman takes this moment to begin his bullying!
これを契機に班長大槻の
イジメが動き出す
Devious bullying!
陰湿なイジメ！
キツくて危険な作業の割り当て
Deliberately assigning the most dangerous jobs!
人の嫌がる時間外の病人の世話
The hated overtime hours nursing!
ゴミ出し
KP duty!
さらに日常的 嫌がらせ
And daily harassment!
Pouring water over the sugar cubes which formed their rare luxuries!
カイジらの蓄え
数少ない嗜好品の角砂糖が水浸し
And dirty water! They were ruined!
しかも汚水　台なしに！
どうして　どうして… ひどい…
Why? Why!? This is terrible!
着替えには生ゴミ
Garbage in their changes of clothes!
靴は泥詰め！
Filling their boots with mud!
Idiots! They're total idiots!
バカだ　あいつは本当にバカだ
班長とぶつかるなんて
そんなことして何の得がある？
They can't fight the foreman! It's impossible!
おい
Look out!
危ない！
カイジさん
Kaiji!
ハア…
もう許せない　こうなったら
みんなで班長を…
Fuck him! We need to kill him before he kills us!
よせ　バカ言うな
だって…
Stop it. That's crazy talk.
But...
Listen, Miyoshi. If anything, I need to thank the foreman.
いいか 三好　俺は逆に
感謝したいくらいなんだぜ 班長に
はあ？
奴は自分のやってることが
He doesn't realize what what he's doing will cause.
どういう結果を生むか
まるで分かってない
嫌がらせをすればするほど
Every trick he pulls just tightens the noose around his own neck.
奴は自分で自分の首を
絞めてるんだ
So I forgive him for this.
だから これぐらいは
許してやろうじゃないか
It's only generous.
寛容な精神で
And! And!!!
そして そして待ちに待った
その日が来た！
The day they awaited arrives!
85 days after the day they decided! Two missed paydays after!
決起の日から85日
途中 ２度あった給料日を
やり過ごし
カイジたちは
ついにやり遂げたのだ！
Kaiji and the others have nearly accomplished their goal!
Complete payback!
完全返済 借金生活の解消を！
An end to the debtor's life!
そう 今日は給料日
Yes, today is payday!
３ヵ月ぶりの給料日
The first payday in three months!
クズどもが
Those losers...
How did those losers pull it off?
どうしてできるんだ？
あんなクズどもが
How could they endure?
どうしてあんな忍耐を…
Tanaka... Arikawa...
田中　有川
Awano... Hattori...
淡野　服部
Kitagawa... Takahashi...
北川　高橋
カイジ君
Kaiji.
What a surprise.
驚いたな　案外 ガマン強いんだな
I never expected you to hold out.
まあ 今回のところは
褒めといてやるわ
Congratulations are in order.
おめでとうよ カイジ君
見直したよ
Good job, Kaiji. I'm impressed.
あっ 何っ！
What!?
He finally receives it! His entire, ungarnished salary!
ついに得る
ピンハネされていない正規の給料
92,000 perica!
９万1000ペリカ！
Hey, that's rude!
コラ 失礼だぞ！
その場で改めるなんて
What are you doing checking it there?
Don't you trust us!?
信用してねえのか
俺たちのことを！
Of course not!
当たりめえだろ！
信用できるはずがねえ
I could never trust you brutes!
鬼畜じゃねえか お前らは
You're beasts who sacrifice your comrades for your own profit!
お前らは自分の利益のために
仲間を犠牲にする鬼畜！
Beasts!
Everyone, check yours.
みんなも確認しろよ
何と言われようと その場で
If we're going to object, it's now or never.
Once we leave this room, that's it.
一度 離れたら
もうそれっきりだぞ
はい
お… おお…
Okay!
このクソガキ…
This shithead!
この男 黒崎義裕
This man, Yoshihiro Kurosaki...
利根川失脚後 帝愛グループ
ナンバー２になった人物
Became #2 in the Teiai Group after Tonegawa's failure!
あの男だろ？
はっ？
Him, huh?
利根川を失脚させた野良犬
He's the stray who brought down Tonegawa?
人騒がせなカイジとかいう男は
Kaiji the troublemaker?
ええ　よくご存じですね
Yes. I see you're already well-informed.
フフッ 実は今日ここに来たのは
それが楽しみでもあったんだ
To be honest, I was hoping to see more of him today.
どんな男かと思ってね
I wonder what kind of man he is?
少しアップにしてくれるか？
はい
Can you zoom in a bit?
Yes, sir.
フフフ… なるほど野良犬だ
Quite a stray.
典型的な野良犬
The very picture of a stray.
しかし この地下に落ちても
まだ抜けていないようだな
But even having fallen so far, his fangs haven't come out yet.
牙は
そして 大盆開帳！
And the table opens!
Normally, all-comers underground chinchirorin
本来 全班参加自由の
地下チンチロは
was set for the first and third Saturday of the month!
第１ 第３土曜の夜
月２回開帳がここの決まり
But since this month has five Saturdays, there is a special night of gambling on payday!
だが 今月は第５土曜まである月
しかも
給料日と重なるという特異日
A wild night which comes but a few times a year!
年に数回 訪れる嵐の夜！
In the best of times, such a night is wildly pivotal!
そんなただでさえ物騒な
大荒れ必至の夜
But tonight, a rumor gallops through the depths of the earth!
今夜 その嵐に拍車をかける
ある噂 風評が
この地下を巡っていた
まことしやかに！
A rumor with the ring of truth!
カイジたち４５組が
That tonight is the night Kaiji and the 45s turn on the foremen's clique!
班長グループに
噛みつくであろうと！
なかなか動かないな 連中
They're not making their move.
Nothing wrong with being cautious.
だが慎重になるのも無理はない
引くに引けない勝負になって
金の乗せ合いになったら
If it comes down to a battle of bankrolls, Ohtsuki has the advantage.
圧倒的に大槻が有利
カイジらは６人全員集めても
54万ペリカ
Even if Kaiji and the others put all their money together, they have 540,000 perica.
But as you know, Ohtsuki saves up his cut as a foreman for gambling money.
だが大槻は知っての通り
班長暮らしで
莫大な金を蓄えている
If I had to guess, I'd say he has at least a million perica.
少なく見積もって
1000万ペリカはある
ああ 50万なんて
ゴミみたいなもの
Half a mil will lose to that any day.
その気になれば
あっという間に潰せる
He can finish them off any time he wants.
潰されてたまるか
I won't let that happen!
Why do you think I endured for so long?
何のために耐えてきたと思ってる
ただタイミングが難しい
But the timing is going to be tough...
When to wait, and when to bet heavy...
勝負の持っていき方
バクチの導入のし方が
ここでしくじると…
If I mess this up...
All my savings, all my endurance, all my planning will be wiped away!
今まで積み重ねてきた忍耐
策略が全て水の泡
気づかれたらダメだ
俺たちの必勝の骨組み
I can't let him figure out how we're going to win...
If he gets a whiff of it, the door to victory closes tight...
そのにおいを敵に気づかれたら
火薬庫の扉は閉ざされてしまう
勝利への道が！
こっちから動くのは
最小限にとどめなければならない
I need to finish him with my first move!
Wait for him to make a move...
ここは奴に動いてもらうんだ
それが一番いい
それが一番ナチュラル
That's it. That will come off the most natural.
Come on!
さあ来い
俺たちをまた４５組に
落としたいんだろ？
You want to make us 45s again, don't you!?
さらにこの大ギャラリーの前で
勝ちきり 誇示をしたい
You want to show off by beating us in front of this audience!
You want to show off your luck in front of everyone!
己の勝負強さを見せつけたい
今 満座の前で！
You want everyone to be jealous!
欲しいんだろ その羨望
その注目！
You want that attention!
All right!
よっしゃー！
いただき いただき
I win, I win.
You know, I've had the feeling that someone rotten is watching me.
何かさっきから見とるのう
性根の腐った奴が１人
隅っこで
From the corner.
カイジさん
来た
Kaiji!
Here it is!
フフフ… スカッと腹を決めたら
どうだね カイジ君？
Why don't you work up the guts to buy in, Kaiji?
わしら もう対決するしかないんだ
We need to settle this!
Everyone's on edge waiting for our grudge match!
皆 声には出さねど期待しておる
遺恨試合を！
だろ？カイジ君
Right, Kaiji?
You sure?
いいのかよ？
は？
When I join in, playtime's over.
俺が行くとなったら
遊びじゃなくなる
I want to see everything on the table.
張らせてもらうぜ 限界を超えて
なっ バカ！何を言い出すんだ！
そんなことしたら…
What's he saying!? If he does that—
Everything, you say?
限界を超えて か…
それはつまり
マックス２万の限定解除
Meaning, the lifting of the 20,000 limit!
青天井！
No limit!
Yeah.
そうだ
フフフ… バカなことを
How foolish...
が しかし どうしても
それがご所望とあらば仕方ない
But if you want it that badly, I'm not going to argue.
それを受けるのも班長の務め
It's my duty as a foreman to accept!
Come, Kaiji!
来い カイジ！
受けてやる！
I accept!
All right!
やった！
ついに言わせたぞ その言葉！
I've been waiting for you to say that in front of everyone!
みんなの前で！
No limits!
限界を超えて
カイジの命を懸けた戦いが
今 始まる！
Kaiji's life-or-death battle begins!
Kaiji advertisement!
The basis for Kaiji season 2, Gambling Apocalypse Kaiji,
is coming out in special magazine-style volumes!
"Underground slavery" arc. "Escape from the underground" arc.
And now "The bog" arc.
"Silver Ball Avici" arc soon to come...
"Beating the Bog" arc.
And "The Comeback" arc.
Don't miss them!